<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<AutoDriveEditor>
    <version_history><![CDATA[<html>
        <head>
            <title>Version History</title>
        </head>
        <body style="font-size:14;">

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.1.0 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.1.0</h2>

            <ul>
                <li>This update contains a huge amount of code changes, Some new bugs may appear.</li>
                <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Please report any bugs found on the GitHub issues page.</li>
                <li>This version has a total UI overhaul in all area's. Any feedback is appreciated.</li>
            </ul>

            <p><u>Added</u></p>

            <ul>
                <li>Added Theme support. (48 Themes included by default)
                    <ul>
                        <li>User generated themes are supported.</li>
                    </ul>
                <li>Added customizable keybind support.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Added additional 25 keybinds.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added movement widget</li>
                <li>Added the ability to get map images direct from a maps zip file.
                    <ul>
                        <li>It will try to extract both the map/heightmap images from the maps zip file</li>
                        <li>A preview window will show the converted images for confirmation by user.</li>
                        <li>It will autodetect the appropriate folder name to save the files to.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <p><u>Changes</u></p>

            <ul>
                <li>Added basic log viewer, will get updates in future versions.</li>
                <li>Added basic render manager to fix the remaining draw order issue's.</li>
                <li>Complete UI overhaul
                    <ul>
                        <li>All custom UI elements support theme preferences.</li>
                        <li>Moved some menu options to button dropdown panels.</li>
                        <li>Re-arranged remaining menu items to a more logical order.</li>
                        <li>Replaced all icons with new SVG format variants.</li>
                        <li>Text panel at bottom of window can now be toggled on/off. ( off by default )</li>
                        <li>Moved all configuration buttons to be above map panel.</li>
                        <li>Swapped lower right Autosave + Map Info panels for buttons</li>
                        <li>Changed side panel buttons to a floating toolbar over the displayed map.
                        <li>Each group of side panel buttons can be expanded/collapsed to save space</li>
                        <li>Editor preferences UI has been redone completely.
                        <li>Renamed "Node Colours" tab in config to "Colours" and added more options.</li>
                        <li>Replaced ColorPicker from previous versions with my own implementation.</li>
                        <li>Added default curve type and priority to Curves preferences tab.</li>
                        <li>Added movement widget configuration screen with many configurable options.</li>
                        <li>Added Theme configuration screen.</li>
                        <li>Added Keybind configuration screen.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>MapPanel code
                    <ul>
                        <li>Small reduction in memory usage of MapPanel.</li>
                        <li>Modified the background image drawing to use sub-pixel rendering.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">No more jerky image movement while moving around the map.!</li>
                        <li>Fixed precision issue's that caused the grid to not align with the map image.</li>
                        <li>Fixed grid aligning issues with odd numbered snapping values.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li> Image Importing
                    <ul>
                        <li>Modified the DDSReader code to drastically reduce memory usage.
                        <li>Swapped buffering of DDS image in memory to chunk loading.
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px"><b>NOTE</b>: Slightly increases conversion times, but the trade-off is acceptable.</li>
                        <li>Tested multiple decode of upto 8192x8192 DDS Files with Xmx memory set at 1024MB.
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Previous versions failed 100% of the time with XmX memory set at 1024MB.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Should no longer see the DDS Decode OutOfMemory error, Please report if you do. </li>
                        <li>Added progress bar to the DDS conversion, avoids the editor looking like it's frozen.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li> Node Height Calculation
                    <ul>
                        <li>Updated node height calculation from terrain, general improvement in accuracy.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Drastically reduces the chances of nodes being under the terrain, but</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">the trade-off is that they can be slightly higher than previous versions</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Undo/Redo
                    <ul>
                        <li>Completely re-done the underlying code for undo/redo.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Any critical changes to a node network is now handled by only the SnapShot class.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">Hopefully this kills the long-standing/hard to track down network corruption bug.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Curve changes.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Complete re-write of all curve code, added functionality, removed duplicate code.</li>
                        <li>Added CurveManager class to maintain all curve creation/removal.</li>
                        <li>Added preliminary support for registering other curve types.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">No release ready examples, one development type is included.</li>
                        <li>Added a flip path direction button to curvePanel.</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">It will swap the start/end/control points to maintain the curve shape.</li>
                        <li>Combined all the current Bézier curve types into a single button.</li>
                        <li>You can now adjust the number of control points while previewing the curve.</li>
                        <li>Many curves can be active at the same time.</li>
                        <li>Curve panel will auto adjust to the currently selected curve</li>
                        <li>On curve commit, any existing nodes that overlap the preview nodes
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">will be used instead on generating new ones.</li>
                        <li>If multiple curves in progress, any curve can be cancelled/commited by</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">selecting any of the curves control nodes and pressing commit/cancel in</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">the CurvePanel</li>
                        <li>First control node will be automatically selected on new curve creation.</li>
                        <li>When adding a new control node, it will be automatically selected.</li>
                        <li>Last selected control node is remembered on button selection/deselection.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>LinearLine Changes
                    <ul>
                        <li>LinearLine type can be changed while in progress using the assign shortcut key.</li>
                        <li>Linearline end points will now snap to any existing points close to it.
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added visual indicator to alignment buttons to show align axis</li>
                <li>Added a confirm dialog to menu item "Clear List", avoids accidental deletions.</li>
                <li>Updated Log4J to version 2.25.3</li>
                <li>Removed all dependencies for ColorPicker.</li>
            </ul>

            <p><u>Fixes</u></p>

            <ul>
                <li>Fixed multi select edge case with curve control nodes.</li>
                <li>Fixed in progress curves persisting after loading a different config.</li>
                <li>Fixed create end node of linear lines not working.</li>
                <li>Fixed decimal issues with PropertyChangeNumberFilter.</li>
                <li>Fixed none fatal NullPointerException in EventTriggerNumberFilter.</li>
                <li>Fixed incorrect search time being calculated for KDTree search.</li>
                <li>Fixed many small rendering issues.</li>
            </ul>

            <p><u>Localization</u></p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added a lot of new strings to support the updated UI.</li>
                    <li>Removed a lot of unnecessary/redundant entry's.</li>
                </ul>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.9 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.9</h2>
            <p><u>Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Load config crash when reading Parking Spots</li>
                <li style="list-style-type: none; margin-left: 10px">FS25 changed how vehicle ID's are stored in vehicles.xml</li>
            </ul>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.8 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.8</h2>
            <p><u>Fixed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed Editor not applying correct default window height when no config found.</li>
                <li>Fixed 'Display HeightMap' not working after heightmap import.</li>
                <li>Fixed 'Save Imported Image' not working.</li>
            </ul>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.7 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.7</h2>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added Freeform selection
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>Right click on the selection button in "edit" Panel to toggle between regular</li>
                        <li>and freeform, any other function that allows multi selection will use whatever</li>
                        <li>selection method you set. </li>                       
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added Ability to hide selected nodes/connections.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Added "Show/Hide" buttons in toolbar, hides user selected nodes/connections.</li>
                        <li>Added Transparency slider to Config, select how hidden they are ( 0 - 100% )</li>
                        <li>Added select/ignore hidden nodes/connection button (right click to toggle)</li>
                        <ul>
                            <li><b><u>NOTE</u></b>: This setting also effects the functionality of allmost all of the 'Nodes'</li>
                            <li style="list-style-type: none;">panel buttons, If something is not selecting, check this setting first</li>
                        </ul>    
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added a Flip Connections button
                    <ul>
                        <li>Allows you to swap the direction of any connection, also supports multi-select</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added support for displaying and properly maintaining parking spots <a href="https://github.com/rhaetional">@rhaetional</a>
                    <ul>
                        <li><b>IMPORTANT...</b> only works for standard configs (not routeManager configs)</li>
                        <li>If a vehicles.xml is in the same folder as the config, it will read all the</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">parking spot from each vehicle and visually display them.</li>
                        <li>When saving a config, the vehicles.xml will be updated to reflect any</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">changes to the node/marker order.</li>
                        <li>For more info, see the issue section on GitHub <a href="https://github.com/KillBait/AutoDrive_Course_Editor/issues/30">(issue #30)</a></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>      
                <li>Added Menu option to move out-of-bounds nodes back into editable area <a href="https://github.com/rhaetional">@rhaetional</a></li>
                <li>Added a recent files menu, stores the 10 previously loaded configs.</li>
                <li>Added the currently used Autosave settings to the info panel.</li>
                <li>Added help menu item containing a link for help on creating map images for the editor.</li>
                <li>Added a 'Display' menu to allow turning off parking/marker icons and marker names.</li>
                <li>Added safeguards against network corruption
                    <ul>
                        <li>As i have no re-producible cases, i have target the obvious places</li>
                        <li>A dialog will appear if triggered, please consider reporting if found</li>
                        <li>Safeguards should trigger before anything incorrect is committed</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Changed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Grid size/max zoom settings are saved to/restored from the editors config for known maps.</li>
                <li>MapPanel rendering improvements.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Configs with large amount of nodes will see the most speed increase.</li>
                        <li>Changed the way nodes are rendered to significantly reduce the z fighting</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">when nodes are close together and drawn connections overlap.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li> 
                <li>Added timers to node size buttons, can now single click or click + hold to adjust size.</li>
                <li>Arrow pointers scale down when the distance between nodes cannot support their full size.</li>
                <li>Replaced the overlapping nodes search function with a more optimised KDTree version.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Removes a possible Concurrency Exception when nodes are moved while scan in progress.</li>
                        <li>Previous versions used a brute force method, the number of searches was the total</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">number of nodes squared, the performance hit was fine for a low quantity</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">of nodes, but, on a large number of nodes it was astronomical.</li>
                        <br>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"><u>Old search function performance</u></li>
                        <br>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"> - 5000 node config, number of searches was 250,000 (5000²)</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"> - 70,000 node config, the number of searches was 4,900,000,000 (70,000²)</li>
                        <br>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">Nearly 5 billion searches for a 70,000 node search!, this is why it took so long</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">on large node configs, the search function had to be threaded otherwise the editor</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;">would be frozen until the search was finished, that could be 30+ seconds.</li>
                        <br>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"><u>Old vs New search times</u></li>
                        <br>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"> - Small config with 5,000 nodes (200ms old version, 17ms new version)</li>
                        <li style="list-style-type: none;"> - Large config with 70,000 nodes (42sec old version, 0.6sec new version)
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Adjusted zoom in/out scaling, getting to max zoom requires much less wheel scrolling.</li>
                <li>FileChoosers used for loading anything are now Read-Only to avoid accidental renaming.</li>
                <li>Moved "Rotate nodes" button to the "Nodes" Panel.</li>
                <li>Added keyboard shortcut for moving nodes ( 'M' toggles move on/off ).</li>
                <li>Changed selection preview of to reflect node and connection type changes </li>
                <li>Updated Log4J to v2.20.0</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Fixed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed the long-standing OutOfBounds exception on restoring nodes
                    <ul>
                        <li>Finally found a re-producible case by sheer luck during testing before release</li>
                        <li>May help with the rare cases on config corruption</li>
                    </ul>
                </li> 
                <li>Fixed a macOS file separator issue in RoutesXML <a href="https://github.com/rhaetional">@rhaetional</a></li>
                <li>Fixed 'out of bounds error' calculating heightmap position on high map scales.</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case where the displayed map image could be moved beyond the edge of mapPanel.</li>
                <li>Fixed mismatched map image/displayed node network scale when editor window is resized.</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case for config corruption in LinearLine undo/redo.</li>
                <li>Fixed known map/node size not being applied when loading a routes XML.</li>
                <li>Fixed unable to zoom in/out due to setting max zoom to less than current.</li>
                <li>Fixed changing autosave max interval not enabling apply buttons.</li>
                <li>Fixed changing autosave interval not applying the new value correctly.</li>
                <li>Fixed missing overlap check with add node undo/redo.</li>
                <li>Fixed possible config corruption when deleting a node that overlapped other nodes.</li>
                <li>Fixed short linear lines not setting start node flag properly to subprio node.</li>
                <li>Many other small fixes i forgot to document</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li style="list-style-type: none;"><b><u>Happy Holidays 2023 / New Year 2024</u></n></li>
            </ul>    



            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.6 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.6</h2>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Preview while multi selecting, can see what nodes are selected while dragging the mouse.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Fixed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed inverted selection on grid snapping button.</li>
                <li>Fixed Cut/Copy/Paste not working due to non updated menu items.</li>
                <li>Fixed Rotation centre offset changing/control node jumping on Undo/Redo.</li>
                <li>Fixed crash due to missing entries in <KnownMapSettings> key (EditorConfig.xml)</li>
            </ul>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.5 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.5</h2>
            <p><u><b>NOTE:-</b></u></p>
            <ol type="1">
               <li>From this release, the editors localization file is included in the release ZIP file ( as requested )</li>
               <li>This release includes some features that were for v1.1, i've included them as they were ready</li>
            </ol>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Rotation button added to sidebar, replaces the temporary 'Rotation' menu.</li>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Node selection works like the other buttons, click drag the diamond node to rotate.</li>
                        <li>Right click the rotation icon to set the number of degree snapping.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Grid option buttons added to sidebar, replaces the 'Grid' menu.</li>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Grid on/off button for displaying the grid, right click to open grid settings.</li>
                        <li>Grid snapping on/off button, can be right-clicked to toggle subdivision snapping.</li>
                        <li>Keyboard shortcuts remain the same, G (Grid On/Off), S (Snapping On/Off), D (SubDivision On/Off).</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added config option to lock the toolbar. ( no more accidental moving )</li>
                <li>Added version history window. ( in 'Help' menu ) </li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Changed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Adjusted how a configs XML is parsed to create the node network
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>A massive loading performance increase for networks with large amounts of nodes</li>
                        <li>and lots of incoming/outgoing connections.</li>
                        <br>
                        <li>e.g</li>
                        <br>
                        <li>A test config i have with 75,797 nodes ( ~170,000 incoming/outgoing connections )</li>
                        <li>    v1.04 - 89.2 seconds to create the node network</li>
                        <li>    v1.05 - 1.4 seconds to create the same node network!!</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Adjusted the location priority when trying to load a mapImage or heightMap.</li>
                <li>Removed the now redundant rotation menu.</li>
                <li>Removed the now redundant grid menu.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added a missing class file i forgot to commit. ( EventTriggerNumberFilter.java )</li>
                <li>Fixed Copy/Paste copying control nodes by accident.</li>
                <li>Fixed 'Show Heightmap' menu not switching back to map image if using the default image.</li>
                <li>Fixed Crash on startup if no EditorConfig.xml was found.</li>
                <li>Fixed failing to load a Routes XML due to a parsing error.</li>
                <li>Fixed node focus keybinding 'F' working inconsistently</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case where linear lines created an end node by mistake.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Localization</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Removed redundant entries</li>
                <li>Added new entries</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>


            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.4 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.4</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Colour tab added to config menu, changing the colours of nodes/connections is now possible.</li>
                <li>Added functionality to Linear lines
                  <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                    <li>(Configurable) Can now automatically create an end node if you do not select one.</li>
                  </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changed</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Major rework of the GUI code
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>Moved all the GUI button functionality out of main code and into their own classes, fixes a</li>
                       <li>multitude of odd behaviours with buttons and mouse clicks.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>(Configurable) Connection arrows can now be drawn as solid or just lines.</li>
                <li>Added keyboard shortcut "F", will centre selected node in viewport.</li>
                <li>Added Linear Line Tab to config window.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Added toggle option for connections having solid arrows. (on by default)</li>
                        <li>Added toggle option to create end node if none selected.</li>
                        <li>Moved Linear Line Spacing option from general tab to Linear Line Tab.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Changed how known maps are stored in Editor.xml, old configs will be updated on next save.</li>
                <li>Updated default en_US locale file.</li>
                <li>Updated Log4j to v2.19.0.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Editor will no longer crash if a missing locale string is found, will show an error in log file.</li>
                <li>Fixed continuous zoom in/zoom out causing the actual zoom levels to drift over time.</li>
                <li>Fixed Linear Line preview not showing correctly if subprio was selected.</li>
                <li>Fixed linear line end position not updating on zoom in/out.</li>
                <li>Fixed node locations having excessive decimal places. ( now limited to three, same as AutoDrive )</li>
                <li>Fixed multiple curve GUI issues.</li>
                <li>Fixed in-progress curve draw order issue's.</li>
                <li>Fixed curve control point visibility.</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case with movement scaler not applying to curves control nodes.</li>
                <li>Fixed issue where certain types of connections were being rendered as Dual connections in error.</li>
                <li>Fixed inconsistent interpolation nodes Y values on new linear lines.</li>
                <li>Fixed overlap warnings and number of overlap nodes not updating properly.</li>
                <li>Fixed various potential null pointer exceptions.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.3 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.3</h3>
            <p><u>Bug Fixs</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed downloading of map images and heightmaps from GitHub repository.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.2 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.2</h3>
            <p><u>Changed</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Reworked version update notification to display the updates release notes.</li>
            </ul>
            <b><u><i>NOTE-:</i></u></b>
            <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                <li>It is active, but you won't see it until the next update is released. :)</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.1 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.1</h3>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed "Save Successful" dialog appearing for autosave and merge backups.</li>
                <li>Fixed autosave and merge nodes switching the active config to the backup.</li>
                <li>Fixed Editor titlebar not showing the map name after certain operations.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 1.0.0 -->
            <!------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.0</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added configuration window. ( finally.... )</li>
                <li>Changed the buttonbar to JToolbar
                    <ul>
                        <li>You can now dock it to the left, right or top of the map panel or detach it completely.</li>
                        <li>The toolbar position ( left/right/top ) is saved in the editor config.</li>
                        <li>The toolbar can be detached from the editor, but this state/position is not saved on exit.</li>
                        <li>By default the toolbar is now located on the left of the window.</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
                <li>Added Options Panel to toolbar, it contains buttons for the follow options
                    <ul>
                        <li>Increase/Decrease the displayed node size.</li>
                        <li>Opening the configuration window.</li>
                        <li>Turning on/off the continuous connection option (left-click on the button to toggle).</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changed</u>
            <ul>
                <li>A large amount of time has been put into code changes/cleanup
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>The majority of bugs fixed in this release were found during the testing of unrelated features</li>
                        <li>and there is a possibility new bugs have been introduced, please report them if you find one.</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
                <li>Adjusted the undo function of "Delete nodes" for a massive speed increase
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li><b>e.g.</b> restoring 12,000 nodes on v0.90 took 8.5 seconds, v1.0 takes 0.15 seconds!!.</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
                <li>Adjusted rendering threads for a small speed increase.</li>
                <li>Added Option to enable/disable autosaving ( enabled by default ).</li>
                <li>Changed negative Z warning icon to red.</li>
                <li>Removed the Option menu as it is no longer needed.</li>
                <li>Map scale is now displayed alongside image and heightmap loaded status.</li>
                <li>Map name is now added to editors titlebar.</li>
                <li>Map Markers are now associated with the actual node and not kept in a separate list
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>Refactored the editor code to remove the use of the MapMarkers class completely,</li>
                        <li>this should prevent map markers moving when copying/pasting and in general use and</li>
                        <li>ensures the saved config map markers are pointing to the correct nodes.</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
                <li>Added warning dialog for Edge case "IndexOutOfBounds" exception in "cut" nodes undo.</li>
                <li>Added 'OutOfMemory' exception dialog for importing DDS images. ( with hint how to correct it )</li>
                <li>The editor version number will change with V1.0 to follow the Semantic Version 2.0.0 standard
                    <ul>
                        <li><a href="https://www.semver.org">www.semver.org</a></li>
                        
                    </ul> 
                </li>
                <li>Updated Log4J to v2.17.2</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed AD 6.0.0.4+ configs not loading due to how the marker ID is stored.</li> 
                <li>Fixed crash when loading the editors XML due to 'LastUsedLocation" being empty.</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case concurrency exception in scan network thread.</li>
                <li>Fixed crash on startup if CurveSliderDefault is greater than CurveSliderMax.</li>
                <li>Fixed NullPointerException when trying to determine the name of a Routes XML map image.</li>
                <li>Fixed loading a Route XML autosave file not detecting the map name.</li>
                <li>Fixed Undo/Redo menu items not disabling when reaching start/end of queue.</li>
                <li>Fixed "Paste In Place" incorrectly adjusting a nodes Y value.</li>
                <li>Fixed "Paste Selection" not calculating the offset to centre of viewport correctly.</li>
                <li>Fixed number of curve points not matching the value of interpolation points slider.</li>
                <li>Fixed multiple node/arrow scaling issue's.</li>
                <li>Fixed linear lines showing unneeded nodes.</li>
                <li>Fixed numeric inputs below minimum value swapping to it's maximum value.</li>
                <li>Fixed numeric inputs buggy negative numbers behaviour.</li>
                <li>Fixed warning icons positions shifting on zoom.</li>
                <li>Fixed imported images not showing correct status in info area.</li>
                <li>Fixed multi selection box enabled when no operation selected.</li>
                <li>Fixed merge nodes backup not working for Routemanager configs.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Localization</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Adjust a lot of locale keys to be more descriptive.</li> 
                <li>Removed unused/redundant strings.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.90.0 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.90.0</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added support for larger map sizes.</li>
                <li>Added internal support for variable size heightmaps.</li>
                <li>Added option to export a heightmap to use as the default heightmap.</li>
                <li>Node size can now be configured ( only through config in this version, next version preferences window)</li>
                <li>Height Maps will be automatically downloaded and used if they are found on the MapImages GitHub.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed connection arrows not scaling properly to node size.</li>
                <li>Minor undocumented bug fixes</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Localization</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Adjusted some locale strings.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.80.0 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.80.0</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added Route Manager XML loading/saving
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>Auto map image detection/loading is working the same way as regular configs</li>
                        <li>but Heightmaps will have to be manually loaded, this will change in release v0.90.0</li>
                    </ul> 
                </li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Editor will now remember the last used autosave slot, ensures oldest save is overwritten on restart.</li>
                <li>The editor now saves the Filechoosers last used location on exit, restores it on load.</li>
                <li>Reverted linear line node scaling until a better system is found</li>  
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed area select not working after menu interaction.</li>
                <li>Minor bug fixes</li>
            </ul> 
            <u>Localization</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Removed unused locale strings.</li>
            </ul>
            <b><u><i>NOTE-:</i></u></b>
            <ul>
                <li>Route Manager loading/saving has only been tested on the FS22 version of AutoDrive</li>
                <li>it is not recommended to use it with FS19 AutoDrive until it has been properly tested.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.70.1 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.70.1</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added a show heightmap menu option.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Re-enabled heightmap loading.</li>
                <li>Added link to GitHub page in about dialog.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed some dialog texts not being correct.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.70.0 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.70.0</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added Autosaving, default interval is 10 minutes, max 10 backups, see options menu to change interval
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>The backup file name is the same as config but with "_autosave_x" added to the end.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added depth alignment option, works the same way as Horizontal/Vertical alignment.</li>
                <li>Added button to Manually edit a nodes X/Y/Z location.</li>
                <li>Added menu item to scan and display overlapping nodes.</li>
                <li>Added warning icon display to nodes, indicates an issue needs looking into.</li>
                <li>Added Paste in Place - Paste nodes into their original location, instead of centred on viewpoint.</li>
                <li>Added a dialog on map scan to specify the range to search for overlapping nodes.</li>
                <li>Added merge nodes menu item, a backup is saved before merging in case something goes wrong.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Creating a connection to a node with a negative Y location will make the node inherit the start
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>nodes Y level, should help to reduce nodes with invalid height's.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Linear lines, Quad Curves and Cubic curves will now calculate and average out any Y height of
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>inbetween nodes ( based on the start/end nodes y level) if no heightmap is available.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>'Fix node height' menu option will now only change nodes that have a large difference in their
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>actual/desired location.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Overlapping node scan now runs in background on config load</li>
                <li>Moving a node now checks if there are any overlapping in new location. ( undo/redo not supported yet)</li>
                <li>FileChoosers now remember the last location used.</li>
                <li>Changed how DEBUG mode is activated, can now be turned on/off from the help menu</li>
                <li>Updated Log4J to 2 17.1</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed overlap scan information only logging to the log file
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>The info will now appear in the text area at the bottom of editor.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Fixed copy/paste buffer duplication</li>
                <li>Fixed import of FS22 map images larger than 8192 x 8192</li>
                <li>Fixed keyboard shortcuts for cut/copy/paste not working</li>
                <li>Fixed adding secondary node creating a regular node :/</li>
                <li>Fixed liner line coordinates mixup from last commit</li>
                <li>Fixed linear line spacing not accounting for the map zoom factor</li>
                <li>Fixed paste selection ignoring no heightmap being loaded</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.60.2 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.60.2</h3>
            <p><u>Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed possible config corruption with "Delete Node" Undo/Redo</li>
            </ul>
            <b><u><i>NOTE-:</i></u></b>
            <ul>
                <li>Mass undo/redo of nodes ( for eg. 200+ nodes ) will take much longer now, in the order of multiple seconds</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.60.1 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.60.1</h3>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed AutoDrive version detection while loading configs.</li>
                <li>Fixed menu item "Fix Nodes Height" being enabled when no heightmap was loaded.</li>
                <li>Fixed QuadCurve and CubicCurve control points freaking out when grid snapping enabled.</li>
                <li>Fixed version check using the wrong repository to check against.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.60.0 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v0.60.0</h3>
            <ul>
                <li>Complete refactor of codebase</li>
                <li>Removed all map images packaged into the JAR file, resulting in huge reduction in filesize.</li>
            </ul>
            <u>Additions</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Added Update check
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>Editor will check github for new versions on startup and display a update message.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added automatic map image downloads
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                       <li>If no matching mapimage can be found during the config load stage, the editor will</li>
                       <li>connect to my other github repository <a href="https://github.com/KillBait/AutoDrive_MapImages">AutoDrive_MapImages</a> and check if an image</li>
                       <li>is available, if so, it will download it and place it in the mapimages folder to re-use.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added terrain heightmap intergration.... Some caveats apply
                    <ul style="list-style-type: decimal;">
                        <li style="margin-bottom: 10px;">The terrain heightmap (terrain.heightmap.png) must be in the same folder as the config your loading,<br>(this is standard for all savegame slot folders)</li>
                        <li style="margin-bottom: 10px;">The height placement will not be exactly level with the ingame terrain, but it should be close, this<br>is due to the terrain heightmap resolution being limited to 2 meters per pixel, whereas ingame terrain<br>is at a much higher resolution. It is strongly recommended you have the node position above<br>the vehicle ingame to compensate for the difference and make sure they are visible.</li>
                        <li style="margin-bottom: 10px;">It cannot account for meshes within the map, so nodes placed over where a bridge (for example)<br> would be will still be on the ground, you will have to manually move them ingame to the correct<br>height, i cannot correct for this issue, it's a known limitation, but better than the original solution</li>
                        <li>If no height map was loaded, adding nodes will revert to the old behaviour of placing nodes at<br>one Y level</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added a menu item 'Fix Nodes Height'
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>Selecting this will scan all nodes and fix the height to the correct values (if a heightmap was loaded)</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changes</u>
            <ul>
                <li>Changed Grid Show/Hide, Grid Snapping, Subdivision Snapping
                    <ul>
                       <li>They are now togglable by a single keyboard press on G, S, D respectivly.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Re-enabled moving multiple nodes with grid snapping enabled, it now works as intended</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>

            <!-------------------------->
            <!-- Start version 0.50.1 -->
            <!-------------------------->

            <br>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">
                Update to v0.50.1<br><br>
                GitHub page created + first commit<br>(previously was pull requests on FS19 AutoDrive GitHub page)
            </h3>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Potential fix for blank FileChooser</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>



            <!------------------------->
            <!---     Templates     --->
            <!------------------------->

            <!--

            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v?.??.?</h3>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
            </ul>
            <u>Changes</u>
            <ul>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
            </ul>
            <u>Bug Fixes</u>
            <ul>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
            </ul>
            <u>Localization</u>
            <ul>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
                <li></li>
            </ul> 
            <hr>

            //-->
 
        </body>
        </html>]]>
    </version_history>
</AutoDriveEditor>
