<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<AutoDriveEditor>
    <latest_version>1.0.5</latest_version>
    <version_notes><![CDATA[<html>
        <head>
            <title>Version Notes</title>
        </head>
        <body>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.5</h2>
            <p><u><b>NOTE:-</b></u></p>
            <ol type="1">
               <li>From this release, the editors localization file is included in the release ZIP file ( as requested )
               <li>This release includes some features that were for v1.1, i've included them as they were ready</li>
            </ol>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Rotation button added to sidebar, replaces the temporary 'Rotation' menu.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Node selection works like the other buttons, click drag the diamond node to rotate.</li>
                        <li>Right click the rotation icon to set the number of degree snapping.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Grid option buttons added to sidebar, replaces the 'Grid' menu.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Grid on/off button for displaying the grid, right click to open grid settings.</li>
                        <li>Grid snapping on/off button, can be right-clicked to toggle subdivision snapping.</li>
                        <li>Keyboard shortcuts remain the same, G (Grid On/Off), S (Snapping On/Off), D (SubDivision On/Off).
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Added config option to lock the toolbar. ( no more accidental moving )</li>
                <li>Added version history window. ( in 'Help' menu ) </li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Changes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Adjusted how a configs XML is parsed to create the node network
                    <ul style="list-style-type: none;">
                        <li>A massive loading performance increase for networks with large amounts of nodes</li>
                        <li>and lots of incoming/outgoing connections.</li>
                        <br>
                        <li>e.g</li>
                        <br>
                        <li>A test config i have with 75,797 nodes ( ~170,000 incoming/outgoing connections )</li>
                        <li>    v1.04 - 89.2 seconds to create the node network</li>
                        <li>    v1.05 - 1.4 seconds to create the same node network!!</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Adjusted the location priority when trying to load a mapImage or heightMap.</li>
                <li>Removed the now redundant rotation menu.</li>
                <li>Removed the now redundant grid menu.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Added a missing class file i forgot to commit. ( EventTriggerNumberFilter.java )</li>
                <li>Fixed Copy/Paste copying control nodes by accident.</li>
                <li>Fixed 'Show Heightmap' menu not switching back to map image if using the default image.</li>
                <li>Fixed Crash on startup if no EditorConfig.xml was found.</li>
                <li>Fixed failing to load a Routes XML due to a parsing error.</li>
                <li>Fixed node focus keybinding 'F' working inconsistently</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case where linear lines created an end node by mistake.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Localization</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Removed redundant entries</li>
                <li>Added new entries</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Visit the Release Page <a href="https://github.com/KillBait/AutoDrive_Course_Editor/releases">Here</a>.</p>
        </body>
        </html>]]>
    </version_notes>
</AutoDriveEditor>