<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<AutoDriveEditor>
    <latest_version>1.0.4</latest_version>
    <version_notes><![CDATA[<html>
        <head>
            <title>Version Notes</title>
        </head>
        <body>
            <h3 style="font-family:verdana;">Update to v1.0.4</h2>
            <p><u>Added</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Colour tab added to config menu, changing the colours of nodes/connections is now possible.</li>
                <li>Added functionality to Linear lines</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>(Configurable) Can now automatically create an end node if you do not select one.,/li>
                </ul>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Changes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Major rework of the GUI code to move the functionality out of main code and into their</li>
                <ul style="list-style: none;">
                    <li>own classes, fixes a multitude of odd behaviours with buttons and mouse clicks.</li>
                </ul>
                <li>(Configurable) Connection arrows can now be drawn as solid or just lines.</li>
                <li>Added keyboard shortcut "F", will centre selected node in viewport.</li>
                <li>Added Linear Line Tab to config window.</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added toggle option for connections having solid arrows. (on by default)</li>
                    <li>Added toggle option to create end node if none selected.</li>
                    <li>Moved Linear Line Spacing option from general tab to Linear Line Tab.</li>
                </ul>
                <li>Changed how known maps are stored in Editor.xml, old configs will be updated on next save.</li>
                <li>Updated default en_US locale file.</li>
                <li>Updated Log4j to v2.19.0.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><u>Bug Fixes</u></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Editor will no longer crash if a missing locale string is found, will show an error in log file.</li>
                <li>Fixed continuous zoom in/zoom out causing the actual zoom levels to drift over time.</li>
                <li>Fixed Linear Line preview not showing correctly if subprio was selected.</li>
                <li>Fixed linear line end position not updating on zoom in/out.</li>
                <li>Fixed node locations having excessive decimal places. ( now limited to three, same as AutoDrive )</li>
                <li>Fixed multiple curve GUI issues.</li>
                <li>Fixed in-progress curve draw order issue's.</li>
                <li>Fixed curve control point visibility.</li>
                <li>Fixed edge case with movement scaler not applying to curves control nodes.</li>
                <li>Fixed issue where certain types of connections were being rendered as Dual connections in error.</li>
                <li>Fixed inconsistent interpolation nodes Y values on new linear lines.</li>
                <li>Fixed overlap warnings and number of overlap nodes not updating properly.</li>
                <li>Fixed various potential null pointer exceptions.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Visit the Release Page <a href="https://github.com/KillBait/AutoDrive_Course_Editor/releases">Here</a>.</p>
        </body>
        </html>]]>
    </version_notes>
</AutoDriveEditor>